Scope refers to which parts of a program a variable can be referenced or used from.
النطاق هو الأجزاء من برنامج التي يمكن منها الإشارة إلى متغيّر ما واستخدامه.
If a variable is created inside a function,
إذا تم إنشاء متغيّر داخل دالة،
it can only be used within that function.
فإنه يمكن استخدامه ضمن تلك الدالة فقط.
Consider these two functions,
تأمل هاتين الدالتين،
word count and nearest square.
عدد الكلمات والمربع الأقرب.
The first function uses answer to count words in a document.
تستخدم الدالة الأولى المتغيّر answer لعد الكلمات في مستند.
The second function uses answer to check values while searching for the nearest square.
الدالة الثانية تستخدم answer للتحقق من القيم بينما تبحث عن المربع الأقرب.
Both functions include this answer variable,
كلتا الوظيفتان تحتويان على متغيّر answer هذا،
but they are distinct variables that can
لكنهما متغيّران مختلفان
only be referenced within their respective functions.
لا يمكن الإشارة إليهما إلا كل واحد ضمن دالته.
Alternatively, we might have a variable defined outside of functions, like this.
كما أنه يمكن أن يكون لدينا متغيّر معرّف خارج الدالات، هكذا.
And we can access it anywhere outside or within these functions.
ويمكننا الوصول إليه في أي مكان خارج تلك الدوال أو داخلها.
Scope is essential to understanding how information is passed throughout programs,
النطاق أساسي جداً لفهم كيف يتم تمرير المعلومات عبر البرامج،
in Python, and really any programming language.
في Python أو في أي لغة برمجة أخرى.